Andrew Greer

Web Developer | Charlotte, NC, 28208 | Email: andrewgreer2015@gmail.com | Phone: (828)773-8001 | Portfolio: https://andrewpaulgreer.github.io/andrew-portfolio/

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/andrewpgreer/Github: https://github.com/andrewpaulgreer |

Summary:

I am currently a front-end developer and graduate of the UNCC coding bootcamp. I specialize in the MERN stack for web development, including kills in both the front end and back end. Ideally I would love to work with several current, and up to date technologies with relation to front-end development.

Skills:

Front-end: HTML 5, CSS3, Javascript, React, jQuery, Ajax, RESTful API creation/consumption, handlebars.js, Bootstrap, Bulma, Twilio, Twilio Flex, TwiML.

Backend: Node.js, MySQL, Mongodb, MySQL Server, express, sequelize ORM, Mongoose ORM passport.js.

Projects:

Let's Guess | https://github.com/lynseahoss/Lets-Guess | https://andrewpaulgreer.github.io/andrew-portfolio/

Let's Guess is an online browser based rendition of the classic "Guess Who?" game. This is a simple, and easy to play game utilizing several current technologies such as React, JS, and MongoDB to power the functionality, logic, and storage.

Technology used:

• React, Bulma, HTML5, Javascript, react router, react context, MongoDB, Mongoose ORM, Node.js, Passport, RESTful API's.

ShopByYou | https://github.com/JRivera-31/ShopByYou | https://shopbyyou.herokuapp.com/

Template based online store to demonstrate knowledge of how an ecommerce platform works. ShopByYou is a full stack application that sends client side input to a MySQL database and retrieves the information using express. *Technology used:*

• Semantic UI, Handlebars, Multer, Google Cloud Bucket, bycrypt.js, Javascript, jQuery, Node.js, Sequelize, MySQL, Express, Express-Handlebars, Passport, Express-Session.

Groovy Concert Search | https://github.com/andrewpaulgreer/Project1 | https://andrewpaulgreer.github.io/Project1/

Groovy Concert Search is a front end application that utilizes jQuery to pull on several different server side APIs and 3rd party APIs to display information to the user about relevant information for concerts, and the preferred city to see a show. *Technology used:*

• HTML5, CSS, Bulma, Particles.js, Moment.js, Javascript, ¡Query, Client-Side APIs.

Professional Experience:

Easyfish Marketing, Charlotte, NC

April 2020 - Present

Frontend Developer

- Building a contact center application configuring Twilio flex with our ActiveCampaign CRM to create an in house call management platform that will allow salespeople / client service workers to manage inbound and outbound calls more efficiently.
- Creating a React Native mobile application for both android and iOS, linking service workers with their company's social media profiles via geo tracking of the metadata on images taken at job sites.

- Mobile application will increase location matched search results on the basis of the geographic location of before/ after photos uploaded to a firebase DB supported by google, and create communication with Google My Businss via API calls.
- In early stages of developing an AI web chat bot through Twilio services, as an add-on to client websites to handle commonly asked questions, in order to reduce customer care costs.
- Participating in daily standup meetings to discuss what we shall be developing for the day.
- Given flexibility and decision making abilities with regards to tools and technologies used in projects.

Technologies Used:

• React.js, React Plugins, React Reducer and Redux (state management), React Native, Javascript, Node.js, Express.js, Axios, MVC, CRUD, HTML, CSS, REST API creation, TwilML scripting, Twilio API, Twilio Flex, Expo CLI, Firebase, Firestore.

Ettain Group, Charlotte, NC

June 2019- April 2020

Technical Recruiter

- Built a network of 100+ professionals with varying skill sets in the technology field who were presented to ettain group's reputable clients in the financial services industry.
- Creatively identify, build relationships with, recruit and place top professionals in positions with Fortune 50 clients.
- Utilize interpersonal skills to create and manage relationships with both the professionals, and clients.
- Exposure to technical interviewing processes for different IT skill sets, which included: Scrum Masters, Agile Coaches, Project Managers, Developers, QA's, BA's, and many more.

Easyfish Marketing, Hickory, NC

July 2017-June 2019

Digital Marketing Specialist

- Cultivated audience engagement metrics to segment and target specific audiences for clients.
- Improved client's digital marketing campaign quality score from a 3.1 to a 9.8 using Google quality score scale.
- Lowered the average client digital marketing cost by 20 percent by improving quality scores.
- Crafted effective and stunning advertisements through Google Search, Google Display, Facebook, and Instagram.
- Communicated with clients and team members through use of project management software.

Leadership:

President of the Eta Beta Chapter of Sigma Nu Fraternity

East Carolina University

March 2016-Dec. 2016

- Utilized communication and leadership skills to expand an organization from 17 members to 85 members.
- Managed an organization of 85 members, leading them towards the common goal of gaining the approval of a petition, receiving several community service awards in the process.

Education:

University of North Carolina at Charlotte, Charlotte, NC

April 2020 - July 2020

Graduated: May 2019

Full Stack Web Development Certificate

East Carolina University College of Business, Greenville, NC

Bachelor of Science in Business Administration, Marketing

Major GPA: 3.750 Graduated Cum Laude